# Steve Stickel

Lead Software Developer

## Contact

**Address** 

Summerville, SC, 29486

E-mail

stevemstickel@gmail.com

**WWW** 

https://tdsticks.github.io/

#### Skills

- POC / Prototyping
- Jira-based Project
   Management
- Database Design
- Cloud Computing
- Solutions Architect

## Languages

- Python 5 yrs.
- Django 3 yrs.
- SQL 8 yrs
- Node.js 5 yrs.
- React 1 yr.
- AngularJS 3 yrs.
- PHP 3 yrs.

Highly skilled software development professional bringing enormous talents for software design, development, and integration. Offering years of experience in providing solutions and architecture. Background in writing code and developing systems for internal and client-based applications.

## **Work History**

#### 2020-04 -Current

## **Lead Software Developer**

Latcha+Associates, Farmington, MI

- Managing and mentoring a team of four developers in Delhi, India for a dynamic SaaS marketing project in AWS, leveraging Node.js and SendGrid
- Currently leading the development of a unique ecommerce SaaS marketing tool tailored for dealerships, utilizing Django, AWS, and Stripe.
- Contributing as the lead developer in building a
  Django API for an innovative luxury boat
  configurator based on the Unreal Engine, hosted on
  Azure.
- Led the architectural design and implementation of a sophisticated Django-based CMS and API in AWS, enabling seamless connection of VIN and engineering data to marketing content for a Ford pilot AR app.
- Successfully executed several proof-of-concept projects, including a Text-to-Speech generator using IBM Watson, an image and video labeling service leveraging AWS Rekognition, and an ML-based object detection app for iOS tailored for the Shelby GT 500 using TensorFlow.

#### 2018-09 -2020-04

## Software Development Manager

Latcha+Associates, Farmington Hills, MI

- Managed team of two developers to help facilitate various email marketing campaigns for client facing VCI (VW/Audi Credit) account.
- Lead developer in enhancing our email marketing development workflow with Salesforce Marketing Cloud and other custom internal applications.

#### 2016-03 -2018-11

## Senior Web Application Developer

Latcha+Associates, Farmington Hills, MI

 Developed internal web applications for clients and company use to help automate manual processes, such as building email seed list generator and a URL document generator.

- Helped architect an improved Jira-based email development pipeline for agency.
- SME on Jira, Salesforce Marketing Cloud and Silverpop for email marketing division.

#### 2012-02 -2016-01

## **Web Application Developer**

Latcha+Associates, Farmington Hills, MI

- Instrumental in creating Lincoln Experience iOS and Android app with content animation and PhoneGap / JavaScript support.
- Architected and lead developer for Audi Marketing Activity Calendar (MAC) using JavaScript and SIMILE JavaScript library with team of other developers.

#### 2007-08 -2012-02

## **DevOps Engineer**

With A Twist Studio, Rochester Hills, MI

- Oversaw and managed office hardware and software infrastructure.
- Improved upon CG pipeline typing together Shotgun Software, post-production software and render farm using Python and Bash.

### **Education**

1997-09 -	Certificate in 3D Animation: 3D Art,
1999-06	<b>Modeling and Animation</b>

School Of Communication Arts - Raleigh, NC

1993-09 -1997-06 **High School Diploma** Troy High School - Troy, MI

## **Additional Information**

- Co-owner of real estate investing business that my wife and I started back in 2019.
- I enjoy writing trading bots for crypto and Forex markets in my spare time.